The first thing we have to do, is to install an operating system that allows us to easy
我们首先要做的是安装 使我们能够轻松
understand how the whole system works. Windows and OSX are closed systems that make it very
了解整个系统的工作原理。窗户 OSX是一个封闭的系统
hard to understand on a technical level. Though, actually, OSX is very similar to Linux and
在技术层面上很难理解。虽然， 实际上，OSX与Linux非常相似，
a lot of concepts can be transferred. But we will use Linux, because we can for example
很多概念都可以转移。但是 我们将使用Linux，因为例如我们可以
have a look at the Linux Kernel sourcecode to dig deeper. And also most people come from
看看Linux内核源代码 深入挖掘。而且大多数人都来自
a different OS - namely windows or mac - so it will be cool to learn something new.
一个不同的操作系统-即Windows或Mac-所以 学点新东西会很酷的。
There are many many distributions of Linux that all have their own flavour. For example
Linux有许多发行版 都有自己的味道。例如
there is Kali Linux (formerly backtrack), which is a Linux operating system that has
有kali linux（以前叫backtrack）。 这是一个Linux操作系统，
a lot of preinstalled tools intended for penetration testing. There are other Linux distributions
许多预安装的工具都是为了渗透 测试。还有其他Linux发行版
that are more aimed to be used as a standard desktop environment for example Ubuntu.
更倾向于作为标准 桌面环境，例如Ubuntu。
A lot of people run Debian on a server to host some websites. And big companies that need
很多人在服务器上运行debian 一些网站。以及需要
operating systems with support and service contracts they often use Red Hat Enterprise Linux
支持和服务的操作系统 他们经常使用Red Hat Enterprise Linux的合同
And I know many people that build their own Linux experience with Archlinux. And there
我认识很多人 拥有使用ArchLinux的Linux经验。那里
are hundreds of other distributions out there. So just google them.
有上百个其他发行版吗？ 所以只需谷歌搜索。
When you want to first check out Linux, it’s difficult to decide what to go for.
当您想首先查看Linux时， 很难决定要做什么。
I generally just suggest go with Ubuntu. It’s a very popular distribution, it's easy to
我一般建议你和Ubuntu一起去。它的 很受欢迎的发行版，很容易
use because it’s kinda aimed at people that have never used Linux before. So that is what
因为它有点针对那些 以前从未使用过Linux。那就是什么
we will do.
我们会的。
But if you are already experienced with Linux, why not take a weekend and checkout archlinux
但是如果你已经对Linux有了经验， 为什么不花一个周末去看看ArchLinux呢？
and build your system from ground up. You will fail the first time, but learn a lot.
从头开始建立你的系统。你 会第一次失败，但学到很多。
So I will install Ubuntu as a Virtual Machine. It makes it easier for me to record and create
所以我将安装Ubuntu作为虚拟机。 它使我更容易录制和创建
those videos, but it also shows another important tool that is often used for security research,
这些视频，但它也显示了另一个重要的 通常用于安全研究的工具，
because you can quickly setup new systems to test something. Oftentimes you only have
因为你可以快速建立新的系统 去测试一些东西。通常你只有
one physical device, but with VMs you can just run a lot of different systems on a single
一个物理设备，但有了虚拟机，您可以 在一个系统上运行很多不同的系统
machine.
机器。
So first download and install the VMWare Workstation Player. As you can see you can download it
因此，首先下载并安装VMware工作站 玩家。如你所见，你可以下载它
for Linux or Windows. If you are on a Mac you might want to try VMWare Fusion but it
对于Linux或Windows。如果你在Mac电脑上 您可能想尝试VMware Fusion，但它
only has a 30 day trial. Or alternatively use Virtual Box.
只有30天的试用期。或者 使用虚拟机。
Then download the Ubuntu 64bit LTS version. If you want you can make sure that you have
然后下载Ubuntu 64位LTS版本。 如果你愿意，你可以确保
the same version like I do, but it doesn’t really matter.
和我一样的版本，但没有 真的很重要。
This is the VMWare Player and it is like a computer inside your computer. It emulates
这是vmware播放器，它就像 计算机内部。它仿真
a real PC. Basically you simply create a virtual hard drive and install anything you like on
一台真正的PC。基本上你只需创建一个虚拟的 硬盘和安装任何你喜欢的东西
it. We will use this to install and run Linux as a so called guest operating system, which
它。我们将使用它来安装和运行Linux 作为所谓的客户操作系统，它
runs inside the real operating system.
在实际操作系统中运行。
Now let’s create a new Virtual Machine. This will launch a wizard for easy installation,
现在让我们创建一个新的虚拟机。 这将启动一个向导以便于安装，
but we will install the OS ourselves. Then select Linux as Operating System and also
但我们将自己安装操作系统。然后 选择Linux作为操作系统，并且
specify Ubuntu 64-bit. If you wanted to install a different Linux distribution, try to find
指定Ubuntu 64位。如果你想安装 一个不同的Linux发行版，尝试找到
it in the list, if it's not there just select Other Linux and select the matching kernel
它在列表中，如果没有，只需选择 其他Linux和选择匹配的内核
version. Give it a name and just use the default settings.
版本。给它取个名字，然后使用默认值 设置。
Imagine this to be like a real physical computer. To install Linux or another operating system
想象一下这就像一台真正的物理计算机。 安装Linux或其他操作系统
on it you would have to insert the installation medium. So we will insert the the ubuntu .iso
在上面你必须插入安装 培养基。所以我们将插入ubuntu.iso
into the virtual CD drive.
进入虚拟CD驱动器。
When we now start the VM, it will boot from the CD and guides us through the installation.
当我们现在启动虚拟机时，它将从 CD并引导我们完成安装。
There are no important settings for us here right now, so just click next. In a later
这里没有重要的设置 现在，只需单击下一步。在以后
video I want to explain what partitions are, but for now just ignore it and continue.
视频我想解释什么是分区， 但现在，忽略它继续。
After the installation you have to restart the machine, but make sure to remove the installation
安装后必须重新启动 机器，但一定要拆下安装
medium again, so it can boot from the hard drive where it was installed.
又是中等，所以它可以从硬的 安装位置的驱动器。
Login and welcome to Linux. First thing you notice is that the window is inconveniently
登录并欢迎使用Linux。第一件事 注意窗户不方便
small, so we want to increase it. We can use the search field to find the display settings,
小，所以我们想增加它。我们可以使用 查找显示设置的搜索字段，
but the menu doesn’t have the option to set it ta proper 16:9 ratio we want. The 16:10
但是菜单没有选择 把它设置成我们想要的16:9的比例。16:10
ratio is slightly too big and we have scroll bars. So let’s go crazy and immediately
比例太大了，我们有卷轴 酒吧。所以，让我们立刻疯狂起来
check out the command line to fix this. The archlinux wiki is a great place to learn more
请检查命令行以修复此问题。这个 archlinux wiki是一个了解更多信息的好地方
about commands that you use. So it tells us that xrandr is a tool that allows us to configure
关于您使用的命令。所以它告诉我们 xrandr是一个工具，允许我们配置
the monitor. Two open the terminal click on the top left and type in Terminal in the search
监视器。两个打开终端点击 左上角，在搜索中键入终端
bar. And those two commands just add a new option for 1920x1080. Now we also see the
酒吧。这两个命令只是添加了一个新的 1920x1080选项。现在我们也看到
option in the display settings.
显示设置中的选项。
Cool. Now let’s just play a little bit with the command line to get a feeling for it how
酷。现在让我们玩一点 命令行来感受它如何
it works and let’s compare it to the maybe more familiar graphical user interface.
它起作用了，让我们把它和 更熟悉的图形用户界面。
On the left you can see the terminal. And on the right you can see the default file
在左边你可以看到终点站。和 在右侧，您可以看到默认文件
explorer which currently displays the content of the home folder. In fact the terminal on
当前显示内容的资源管理器 主文件夹的。实际上，终点站在
the left is in the same place!
左边在同一个地方！
The first part is the current user. After the @ is the computer or host name. After
第一部分是当前用户。后 @是计算机或主机名。后
the colon you can find the current location. And the tilde is an alias for your users home
可以找到当前位置的冒号。 tilde是用户家的别名
folder. For example if you execute the pwd command, it will display the current location,
文件夹。例如，如果执行pwd 命令，它将显示当前位置，
which is the home of the user liveoverflow. Before we look into more commands, let me
这是用户LiveOverflow的主页。 在我们研究更多命令之前，让我
show you one of the most important source of information for the linux system. It is
给你看一个最重要的来源 Linux系统的信息。它是
the Linux manual. So let’s type man followed by what we are interested in. In this case
Linux手册。那么让我们输入“人”来 我们对什么感兴趣。在这种情况下
pwd. You should get familiar how those man pages look like, because we will use them
随钻测井。你应该熟悉那些人 页面看起来像，因为我们将使用它们
a lot. Right here at the top it says that pwd will print the name of the current working
很多。上面写着 pwd将打印当前工作的名称
directory. At the bottom you get the information that
目录。 在底部，你得到的信息是
you can press h to display a help or q to quit and get back to the command line. So
您可以按H键显示帮助或按Q键 退出并返回命令行。所以
when you press h you will see the summary of less commands. I will show you later what
当你按H时，你会看到摘要 更少的命令。我稍后给你看什么
less is, but for now just think of this as some kind of text editor that displays file
少一点，但现在把它想成 某种显示文件的文本编辑器
content. And this editor uses key input for navigation. So let’s press q to exit the
内容。这个编辑器使用键输入 导航。那么让我们按q退出
help, and q again to exit the manual. Now I will quickly go over some commands to
帮助，然后再次q退出手册。 现在，我将快速浏览一些命令
navigate around the file system. If you don't know them or would like to know more about
在文件系统中导航。如果你不 了解他们或想了解更多
them, you should check out the man pages.
他们，你应该看看手册。
Let’s start with ls which will display the files of the current folder. You can see it
让我们从显示 当前文件夹的文件。你可以看到
looks almost the same, except the graphical interface shows a shortcut to Examples, while
看起来几乎一样，除了图形 界面显示示例的快捷方式，而
ls shows a examples.desktop file. That's weird. Let’s use cat to look at the content of
ls显示一个examples.desktop文件。真奇怪。 让我们用cat来查看
the file and investigate this. Cat just prints the file content in the terminal and you can
文件和调查。猫只是打印 终端中的文件内容，您可以
now see that this seems to be some kind of special file, that defines a type link and
现在看看这似乎是某种 定义类型链接和
name Examples. So the terminal just displays the actual files, while the graphical user
列举例子。所以终端只是显示 实际文件，而图形用户
interface parses the example-content file and displays it in a different way. This is
接口解析示例内容文件 以不同的方式显示。这是
one reason why many people say that linux command line is very simple because you don’t
很多人说Linux的一个原因 命令行非常简单，因为
have to know all those weird features that are different in every program.
必须知道所有那些奇怪的特征 每个节目都不一样。
Now execute ls with the option L to display the files as a list which also provides more
现在使用选项l执行ls以显示 文件作为一个列表，它还提供了更多
information like the file permissions, ownership and date. The first character indicates if
文件权限、所有权等信息 和日期。第一个字符表示
the file is a directory. Maybe you wonder why I say files, while they
文件是一个目录。 也许你想知道为什么我说文件，而他们
are all directories. The reason for that is that in Linux everything is a file.
都是目录。原因是 在Linux中，一切都是一个文件。
Wikipedia even has an entry for “everything is a file” and it reads.
维基百科甚至有“一切”的条目 是一个文件，它可以读取。
This is a defining feature of Unix, and its derivatives - a wide range of input/output
这是Unix的一个定义性特性，它的 衍生产品-广泛的输入/输出
resources such as documents, directories, hard-drives, modems, keyboards, printers and
文档、目录等资源， 硬盘、调制解调器、键盘、打印机和
even some inter-process and network communications are simple streams of bytes exposed through
甚至一些进程间和网络通信 简单的字节流是否通过
the filesystem - as a file. Over time we will understand this better.
文件系统-作为一个文件。随着时间的推移，我们会 更好地理解这一点。
Now add the option 'a' to display all files. 'a' and 'l' are single character option switches,
现在添加选项“a”以显示所有文件。 “A”和“L”是单字符选项开关，
which is indicated by the hyphen prefix. Doesn’t matter if you combine them or specify them
由连字符前缀表示。不 不管你是将它们组合起来还是指定它们
separately. Suddenly you see a lot more files that start
分别地。 突然你看到更多的文件开始
with a dot. Those dotfiles were hidden before. Historically this was a bug and you can read
带点。这些点文件以前是隐藏的。 历史上，这是一个错误，你可以阅读
more about it in this post, but now it’s a feature and dotfiles are often used for
关于这篇文章的更多内容，但现在 功能和点文件通常用于
config files.
配置文件。
Now let’s look at the filesystem. We can use cd to change the directory. Let’s go
现在让我们看看文件系统。我们可以 使用cd更改目录。让我们走吧
to the top of the hierarchical filesystem which starts at slash. Now you can also see
到层次文件系统的顶部 从斜线开始。现在你也可以看到
that the tilde changed to the slash, which is our new current location.
颚化符变为斜线， 是我们现在的新地点。
If you specify a path without a slash it’s a relative path going forward from your current
如果指定的路径没有斜线，则 从你的电流向前走的相对路径
location. If you have a slash, it will be an absolute path. So here are just some examples.
位置。如果你有斜线，它会是 绝对路径。这里只是一些例子。
Maybe you notice the dots and double dots that I am using. If you look at the ls output
也许你注意到了点和双点 我正在使用的。如果你看一下ls输出
again, you notice that there are two files with dots. A single dot is referencing the
同样，您注意到有两个文件 带点。一个点正在引用
current directory. So 'ls' and 'ls .' is exactly the same. A double dot goes one hierarchy
当前目录。所以“ls”和“ls.”就是 相同的。一个双点表示一个层次结构
up. So when you are in your home directory you can use two double dots to got to the
起来。所以当你在你的主目录 你可以用两个双点到达
top.
顶部。
Ok. Slow enough, let’s speed up a bit.
好啊。慢点，我们快点。
'mkdir' makes a new directory 'touch' makes a new empty file
'mkdir'生成新目录 “touch”生成新的空文件
'rm' deletes a file. If you want to delete a folder you have to add the recursive option.
“rm”删除文件。如果要删除 必须添加递归选项的文件夹。
'echo' and a character sequence just prints this text
“echo”和字符序列只是打印 本文
'uname' and uname with different arguments provide information about your machine
“uname”和具有不同参数的uname 提供有关您的机器的信息
'll' is a short cut for 'ls' with multiple parameters
“ll”是“ls”的一个短截线，具有多个 参数
'free' shows you the current memory usage and with the parameter h the numbers will
“free”显示当前内存使用情况 参数h，数字将
be shown in human readable format 'df' shows file system disk space and again
以人类可读的格式显示 “df”一次又一次显示文件系统磁盘空间
with parameter h the numbers are in human readable format
参数h的数字是人类的。 可读格式
'ps' gives information about your currently running processes. With parameters you can
“ps”提供有关您当前的 正在运行进程。通过参数，您可以
also show all processes with memory usage, cpu and more.
同时显示内存使用情况下的所有进程， CPU等。
and id shows you your current user id
ID显示您当前的用户ID
One last important feature to learn about are pipes and redirections. Linux becomes
最后一个要了解的重要功能 是管道和重定向。Linux成为
very powerful once you connect multiple commands together.
连接多个命令后非常强大 一起。
For example echo prints a string. You can redirect this output into a file by using
例如，echo打印一个字符串。你可以 通过使用将此输出重定向到文件
the arrow.
箭头。
When you print the content of a file with cat you can use the horizontal line or also
打印文件内容时， 你可以用水平线或者
often called pipe to redirect the output from “cat” into the input of another program.
通常称为管道，用于重定向输出 “cat”输入另一个程序。
For example you can pipe the output of the 'cat' command into the input of the 'hexdump'
例如，可以通过管道传输 “cat”命令输入“hexdump”
command - a tool that shows you the actual hex values behind each character. And here
命令-显示实际 每个字符后面的十六进制值。这里
the hex '0a' for example, or decimal ten. You should start becoming familiar with hex,
例如十六进制“0a”或十进制十。 你应该开始熟悉Hex，
because you will use it a lot. Check out the manual for ascii characters. You can navigate
因为你会经常使用它。退房 ASCII字符手册。你可以导航
up and down with arrow keys. And exit with q.
上下箭头键。然后退出 Q.
One last thing, you can press arrow key up in the terminal to quickly enter previous
最后一件事，你可以按箭头键向上 在终端中快速输入上一个
commands. And even more powerful is CTRL+R, which opens a search prompt. Now we look for
命令。更强大的是ctrl+r， 打开搜索提示。现在我们寻找
the command where we used for hexdump, and once it found it we can just hit Enter to
我们用于hexdump的命令，以及 一旦找到它，我们就可以按Enter键
execute it. If you want to leave this prompt or generally want to quit running programs,
执行它。如果你想离开这个提示 或者通常想退出正在运行的程序，
you can hit CTRL+C.
您可以按ctrl+c。
Ok cool. That’s it for now so let’s shutdown the system with “shutdown now”.
好酷。现在就这样了，我们停下来吧 “立即关机”的系统。
uh! but what is that. You must be root to shutdown the machine. The root user or also
休斯敦大学！但那是什么？你一定是根 关闭机器。根用户或
called superuser is very powerful, because this user can do everything. But we are currently
所谓的超级用户非常强大，因为 这个用户可以做任何事情。但我们现在
the user liveoverflow. It’s good practice to not use the root user all the time because
用户LiveOverflow。这是很好的做法 不要一直使用根用户，因为
you can do a lot of damage. But there is a command prefix called sudo, which elevates
你可以造成很多伤害。但是有一个 命令前缀sudo，它提升
your privileges. execute id with sudo and you see you are liveoverflow. Execute id with
您的特权。使用sudo和执行id 你看你是活生生的。执行ID
sudo, first enter your password, and then you will see that you executed it as root.
sudo，首先输入密码，然后 您将看到您以根用户身份执行它。
So you can use that now to shutdown the VM.
所以你现在可以用它来关闭虚拟机。
See you next time when we will create our first program.
下次我们将创建我们的 第一个程序。